Ilya Titov

Web Developer

Motivated and experienced professional with a passion for the IT industry. I love solving complex problems and driving business success. Equally comfortable collaborating with teams or working independently, my adeptness at multitasking and time management ensures efficient delivery of results.

EXPERIENCE

Web Developer

Freelance

Sept 2023 - Present - Belgrade

- Developed plugins for linting Markdown files. PR with links to plugins that were successfully accepted into the official repository by remark-lint.
- Created a cross-platform Progressive Web Application that allow users effectively memorize information using spaced repetition technic.
- Actively engaged in open-source projects, notably contributing to the development of an RSS reader that empowers users to separate feeds for useful and entertaining content.

Frontend Developer

Rossiya Segodnya

Aug 2022 - Sept 2023 - 1 year, Moscow

- Transferred the company's outdated website to a modern React-based platform, resulting in a 50% reduction in bounce rate and a 25% increase in user engagement.
- Implemented Redux state management, optimizing load times and enhancing overall performance.

Senior Specialist in the Contract Department

Rossiya Segodnya

Oct 2017 - Aug 2022 - 5 years, Moscow

- Drafted contracts, tailored to the organization's specifics.
- Proficient in tools such as 1C, Excel, and DMS, ensured meticulous document control.

EDUCATION

Master's degree in Economics and Management

Plekhanov Russian University of Economics

2010 - 2015



Email: ilyatitovich@gmail.com

GitHub: github.com/ilyatitovich

LinkedIn: in/ilyatitovich
Phone: +381 62 124 97 70

City: Belgrade

Industry Knowledge

HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript (ES6+), TypeScript, Node.js, UX/UI Design

Tools & Technologies

Figma, Sass, React/Next.js, Vue/Nuxt.js, Redux, SQL, Git, Webpack, Linux

Languages

Russian (native) English (C1 level)

Books and Courses

CS50: Introduction to Computer Science

Edx

Professional JavaScript for Web

Developers

Nicholas C. Zakas

Understanding ECMAScript 6

Nicholas C. Zakas

CSS in Depth

Keith J. Grant

The Algorithm Design Manual

Steven Skiena